Renjith Rajakumar

🔀 renjithkumar993@gmail.com 📞 5195961111 😲 50 Sylvya crt Fredericton NB

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/renjith-rajakumar-109a4051/ https://github.com/Renjithkumar993

Profile

I am currently enrolled in the University of New Brunswick and transitioning into a career in full-stack development and have been learning various front-end and back-end technologies. My current focus is on building my skills in HTML/CSS/Git, JavaScript, Bootstrap, The DOM, APIs, JQuery, JSON, AJAX, team collaboration, Agile development, and project demonstration.

I am also learning Node, ES6, object-oriented programming, Express, MySQL, the MVC paradigm, Sequelize, Progressive Web Apps, React, NoSQL, MERN Stack, and computer science fundamentals to building a solid foundation in full-stack development.

In my previous role, I was a highly experienced IT professional with over 7 years of experience. My expertise included managing and maintaining the System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM), Azure, Exchange, and Security. I have experience working with clients in all industries, from small businesses to large enterprises, to ensure their technology needs are met. I am also highly qualified in the security field, having obtained Cybersecurity certifications such as CHFI (Computer Hacking Forensic Investigator), CEH (certified ethical hacker), and Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer Associate.

Despite my experience in IT, I have found that my passion lies in full-stack development, and I am excited to explore new opportunities in this field. I am confident that my experience in IT, coupled with my new skills in full-stack development, will make me an asset to any team.

Skills

Cybersecurity • System Administration

Microsoft Exchange • Ethical Hacking • Linux

SCCM

Progressive Web Apps ● React ● NoSQL ● MERN Stack ● Computer science fundamentals

Powershell • Incident Management

Microsoft Azure • Office 365

◆ HTML/CSS/Git ◆ JavaScript ◆ Bootstrap ◆ The

DOM ● APIs ● JQuery ●Testing ● Agile

development ● JSON ● AJAX ● Agile

development ● Node ● ES6 ● Object-oriented

programming ● Express ● MySQL ● MVC

paradigm ● Sequelize ● Bulma

Professional Experience

05/2019 - present Fredericton, Canada

Infrastructure Application Analyst

Government of New Brunswick / Gouvernement du Nouveau-Brunswick

- Provide customer service to SNB clients spanning Part 1 (core government departments) and Part 3 (Regional Health Authorities).
- Support the implementation of the Office 365 solution for Exchange and Skype for Business, Cloud Computing.
- Migrate users from Exchange 2010 to Office 365.
- Performing eDiscovery, Mail trace, and troubleshooting emails going to spam and quarantine.

- Recovering soft-deleted mailboxes in an Exchange Hybrid scenario.
- Performed public folder migration.
- Make firewall changes to make the application communicate.
- Assigning Office 365 License according to users' eligibility.
- Provide service to SNB clients and ensure processes and procedures are aligned to the SNB shared services delivery model;
- Monitor the performance of the infrastructure applications and make recommendations for improvement;
- Respond and process Exchange and/or Active Directory support tickets;
- Worked with the SNB Service Desk to establish user management standard operating procedures;
- Assist in the creation and modification of existing user account policies in relation to Office365
- Support the user experience and resolve issues and address concerns

2018 – 2019 Moncton, Canada

Technical Operator

Government of New Brunswick / Gouvernement du Nouveau-Brunswick

- Design and implement application deployment strategies, including the use of collections and task sequences for both Office 365 and other applications.
- Collaborate with other IT teams to identify and prioritize application deployment needs.
- Create and maintain deployment packages for Office 365 applications and other business-critical applications.
- Troubleshoot and resolve deployment-related issues.
- Provide guidance and support to end users on the use of Office 365 applications and other deployed applications.
- Monitor and maintain the overall health of the deployment infrastructure.
- Work with other IT teams to ensure compliance with security and regulatory requirements for application deployment.
- Keep up-to-date with new Office 365 application features and updates, and plan for their deployment within the organization.
- Create and maintain documentation and procedures related to application deployment.
- Provide training to end-users and IT staff on the use of Office 365 applications and other deployed applications.

2018 – 2019 Saintjohn, canada

Information Technology Support Analyst

Wyndham World Wide

- Provided technical guidance for migration, configuration and deployment of Lync.
- Daily provided hands-on administration and maintenance of network equipment including routers and switches. Installed and configures computer equipment with operating systems (OS) and applied
- required software policies and standards to adhere with the company IT security policies.
- Assist in the management and maintenance of the Exchange environment, including Exchange on-premises and Exchange Online.
- Monitor and troubleshoot Exchange-related issues and work with senior administrators to resolve them in a timely manner.
- Assist in the implementation of security and compliance measures for the Exchange environment.
- Provided technical support for corporate users to include setting up computers, user name login credentials, passwords, rights, roles and responsibilities using Active Directory (Computers and Users).
- Notified customer of issue status and followed-up with customers to ensure problems have been resolved satisfactorily and in a timely manner.

• Create and maintain documentation and procedures related to Exchange.

2016 – 2017 Saintjohn, Canada

Technical Support Specialist

Nordia Inc

- Provided software troubleshooting and administration for proprietary software as well as Microsoft Office, Windows 7, Internet Explorer, Java, and Adobe.
- Multitasked across multiple platforms, supporting various programs; technically inclined to navigate
- through several systems to get first call resolution in a timely and orderly fashion.
- Developed rapport with the customer early in the contact, by speaking clearly and concisely, asking excellent probing questions, and ensuring clear understanding of what they need assistance with. Take ownership of their issue.
- Maintained customer records by updating account information.
- Troubleshooting system and network problems and diagnosing and solving hardware software issues.

Technical Support Specialist

Transcom

- Provide first-level technical support to end-users via phone, email, and chat.
- Troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software issues related to desktop computers, laptops, printers, and other IT-related equipment.
- Log and track all incoming incidents and requests in a service management system.
- Follow established service level agreements (SLAs) and incident management procedures.
- Provide guidance and support to end-users on the use of IT-related systems and applications.
- Escalate incidents and requests to the appropriate IT teams as needed.
- Keep accurate and detailed records of all incidents and requests.
- Provide end-user training on IT-related systems and applications.
- Work with other IT teams to ensure compliance with security and regulatory requirements for IT-related systems and applications.
- Keep up-to-date with new IT-related systems and applications and provide guidance on their use.
- Create and maintain documentation and procedures related to IT-related systems and applications.

Certificates

- CompTIA Project+ Certification
 CompTIA
- Computer Hacking Forensic Investigator (CHFI) - EC-Council
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer Associate -Microsoft
- Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) -EC-Council

Education

2010 – 2013 Coimbatore, India Bachelor of computer application, Computer Programming, Specific Applications

Bharathiar University

2014 – 2016 Sarnia, Canada PG Diploma in Information Technology Professional, Network and System

Administration/Administrator

Lambton college

01/2023 Fredericton, Canada **UNB Coding Bootcamp** *University of NewBrunswick*